Kang (Frank) Chen

Undergraduate Student UCLA Henry Samueli School of Engineering & Applied Science Los Angeles, CA 90024 kfrankc.me

frank.chen@g.ucla.edu 510-565-8237 Linkedln: linkedin.com/in/kfrankc Github: github.com/kfrankc

Research Interest I am primarily interested in vision and robot learning, specifically training robots to adapt to novel situations using causal learning. I hope to build robots that can perceive the world as we do.

Education University of California, Los Angeles

Spring 2017

Computer Science B.S.

GPA: 3.34/4.0

Relevant Skills & Courses

C/C++, MATLAB, Octave, Python, Javascript, OCaml

OpenCV, Mathematical Modeling, Algorithms, Data Structures

Academic Experience

Center for Vision, Cognition, Learning, & Art

March 2016 - present

Undergraduate Researcher

- * Research in causal relationships, fluent extraction, and causal learning
- * Implemented detection + tracking modules in OpenCV for teaching robots to fold shirts
- * Built fluent visualization modules to construct action grammars from raw robot data
- * Submitted paper to Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) conference

CS 88S: Undergraduate Student Initiated Education (USIE) September 2016 - present Instructor

- * Designed a 10-week undergraduate computer science seminar designed to introduce students to cybersecurity fundamentals & protecting themselves in cyberspace
- * Topics included general introductions to: computer networking, cryptography, password cracking, wireless vulnerabilities, denial of service attacks

Jet Propulsion Laboratory

June 2015 - June 2016

Computer Vision Research Intern

- * Spearheaded frame by frame tracking of IR multi-bandwidth images
- * Achieved 90% accuracy in segmentation of images using neural network
- * Published two papers at SPIE conferences

Wnrk **Experience**

Workday Application Development Intern June 2016 - present

- * Implemented tax location mapping reports as part of Workday 28 product release
- * Created get/put APIs for Workday Web Services
- * Actively involved in Workday's agile development pipeline

Taboola March - June 2016

Software Engineering Intern

- * Implemented user authentication system using React.js and Node.js
- * Built modules to communicate with Taboola Backstage API from scratch

Daily Bruin

September 2014 - March 2016

Project Manager

- * Spearheaded complete redesign of Spectrum, Daily Bruin's online Photo Blog
- * Led a team to build an interactive web application for UCLA's dorm communities
- * Presented workshops on Sublime Text + Git tools for incoming Daily Bruin staff

Publications

Cross-correlation and image alignment for multi-band IR sensors

Kang (Frank) Chen, Andrew Luong, Mallory Dewees, Xinyi Yan, Thomas Lu, Tien-Hsin Chao, Edward Chow, Gilbert Torres
SPIE Optical Pattern Recognition XXVII 2016 | Baltimore, MA

Intelligent multi-spectral IR image segmentation

Kang (Frank) Chen, Andrew Luong, Stephen Heim, Maharshi Patel, Thomas Lu, Tien-Hsin Chao, Edward Chow, Gilbert Torres Submitted to SPIE Optical Pattern Recognition XXIX 2017

Unsupervised learning of fluents from human demonstrations

Nishant Shukla, Yunzhong He, Kang (Frank) Chen, Song-chun Zhu Submitted to Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) 2016

Honors and Awards

Upsilon Pi Epsilon Honor Society
Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society
True Bruin Distinguished Senior Finalist
Gerald P. Popek Scholarship in Computer Science
Harley L. Woods Family Scholarship

March 2014 - present March 2015 - present November 2016 January 2016 January 2015

Leadership

Resident Assistant

September 2015 - present

* Responsible for a floor of 90 residents in UCLA's residential dorms

IDEA Hacks Organizer

September 2015 - February 2016

* Sponsorship organizer for the largest hardware-focused hackathon in the West Coast

LA Hacks Organizer

January 2015 - present

* Operations organizer for the largest hackathon in the West Coast

Engineering Society of UCLA

September 2014 - June 2015

* External VP for the umbrella engineering club at UCLA

Bruin Entrepreneurs

September 2013 - June 2015

* Led incubator program for UCLA's student entrepreneurs